One single question I
was asked this morning,
I didn't realize how much it was
going to trigger me.
Had to become a video.
Someone said to me, "What
if you dislike marketing?" So here it is,
the reality
check that you need. Everything
is marketing. Everything.
But for some reason, people think
that marketing is some sleazy jargon that
corporations use,
and they use boring terms like return
on investment, spend, total
addressable market.
That's corporate marketing.
So how can I explain why marketing
is everywhere?
Getting laid is also marketing,
and the same people that
struggle to get clients
are the same people that struggle to get
pussy.
Because rather than breaking it down as a
set of
sequences between where you are
and success, you paint narratives.
Incels have given up on marketing.
That's it.
That's why they're incels.
The same way that some people out there
go,
"Oh, I dislike marketing." Well,
guess what?
Incels hate pussy because they're really
bad at getting it.
Any of you that have followed me before
have known and seen me go through the
sequences that I always do, saying
that marketing and getting laid are very
similar. If you want clients,
you need to put yourself in the right
place, AKA the
metaphorical dance floor.
When you're on the dance floor,
you don't try and get
sex, you get numbers.
Then you can market
and prospect yourself to those people
away from the dance floor.
Because even though they're there on your
live stream,
watching your webinar,
watching your YouTube video,
it doesn't mean they're ready
to fuck right now. So instead,
you get some data from them.
Then, over time, you chat, you message,
you court with that
person to the point
that they eventually go,
"Do you know what? Fuck it, I'm in.
Let's have a date." Now, for some people,
the date is doing a sales call.
For other people, the date
is sending them to the landing page.
And then ultimately,
if you go on enough dates with enough
people, some of them
want to fuck. Now, the same way
that some men out there weirdly
think that women don't want to fuck.
Why do you think they're on dating apps?
They want the same thing as you.
All those people on your email list aren't
there because they just fucking felt like,
"Oh, I'll do this bloody nice chap
and this nice lady a favor." They're keen.
They're signaling they're keen.
But it's your job
and responsibility to nurture them to the
point that they want to
do business with you. Not everyone will.
The same way if you get five numbers on a
night out, you'd be lucky if three go on
a date and one puts out. Everything
is marketing.
This is marketing. I'm marketing
that I have the things
that you want.
It's called an appeal to authority.
It's a part of my marketing structure.
Some young lads on a bike.
[revving] I'm then revving it.
I'm marketing to them
young lads. The way we dress,
the way we present ourselves is marketing.
The fact that I don't wear jewelry,
but when I go to dinner, I wear a Rolex,
I'm marketing status. We
are always giving off signals to who we
are, what we've accomplished, what we do.
And even those marketing signals right
now, even my choice of car.
To have something impractical, rare,
expensive.
I am marketing to other men
that want that.
To say you dislike marketing
is to deny that every single thing you
are doing is a form of marketing.
Someone who says, "Oh, I don't really like
marketing," yet still puts makeup on
and does their hair before going out, that
still likes wearing designer clothes.
Do you understand why the whole idea
or premise that you
dislike marketing is fucking stupid?
You are a marketer all the time, 24/7.
The reason that you give your phone back
to someone and say, "No, take another
picture. I didn't look good in
that one," is marketing.
The thought that you dislike marketing
pretty much boils down to the fact that
whatever you are doing is not working.
And that is okay, but
that whole question needs to be reframed.
Instead of what if you dislike marketing,
the question should be, what if my
marketing isn't working?
Because every single one of you has been
to a job
interview before. Marketing.
The way you structure your CV,
marketing. The way you present yourself,
marketing.
The fact you shaved the morning of the
interview, marketing.
The nice houses that you look at,
that you dream of living in, marketing.
Marketing is not manipulation.
Marketing is signals.
And you need to be sending signals out,
not just for the sake of fancy car,
social media following, whatever.
Think of it this way.
Someone right now on my YouTube channel
watching my video can go back and go,
"Wow,
James has put a YouTube video out for
fucking months on end without skipping a
beat. He turns up, he's consistent.
If he does all this for free,
I wonder what I get
if I pay him." Whereas there are
so many of you that don't post enough on
social media, you're scattered, you go
through periods of motivation,
and it's apparent that, yeah, you had two
months that you were highly motivated,
but now you don't really care anymore
because I don't really like marketing.
I don't really love it.
They're going to look at that and go,
"Well,
if you couldn't even do this for free,
how am I going to expect you to do
something with a paid product?" Personal
brand
is about marketing signals to the market.
It's about building a reputation.
Personal brand is what people
are going to say behind you about your
back in a
good way. And whatever niche you're in,
your personal brand is going to be made up
of all of those marketing signals
that you sent out to the market.
All the videos you made,
all the LinkedIn posts that you did,
all the tweets that
you did, all the podcasts
that you attended.
You may, quote unquote,
"not like marketing." But the truth is
you probably just don't like being shit at
marketing.
And if you're shit at marketing,
if you're awkward at making videos,
if you don't
really like your voice on social media,
that's fine. But don't blame marketing.
That's your fault. Same way that
if I go start Muay Thai today,
I'm going to be
shit. Why?
Because I've not really done much Muay
Thai.
If I go start a Spanish class this
afternoon,
I'm probably not going to do that
well at it.
Because je suis parle francais.
The narrative that you don't like
marketing is dangerous because it
is essential
in every single thing you do as a human
being.
Not just in business, but outside.
You want to marry someone sexy?
You're going to have to be good at
marketing.
You want that person to stay with you?
You best be good at marketing.
The sooner you realize everything
is marketing and business just sits within
that,
the quicker you can get on with
understanding that this
is about building and
growing skills in a certain domain.
Everyone is trainable, everyone
is malleable.
You have people that either do the work
or they don't.
Yesterday, working with a client.
"I'm not really sure what to post about."
You've only done 400 fucking
Instagram posts. I've done 5,000.
Do you not think
that you'd get to a stage where I sit
there in front of a camera
and don't have anything to fucking talk
about?
Then today,
someone gave me the gift by asking me a
question.
"James,
what if I don't really like marketing?"
And rather than just answering
that one person, I thought, you know what?
Let's make this a piece of content to help
thousands of people thinking the same
thing,
and by helping them understand this stance
on marketing,
I am Also marketing.
The way I look with my shirt off,
marketing.
The cars that I drive, marketing.
Telling you how much money I made last
month,
marketing. But here's the beauty.
A lot of people will think
that I'm a fucking bellend for the sports
car,
for the watch, for showing revenue.
But that's because I'm being selective in
marketing to the right kind of people.
And if this video has 10,000 views,
and 3,000 think I'm a fucking
bellend,
that's okay because I'm not marketing to
you.
If you do not aspire to have what I'm
building and what I'm growing, you are not
the right person for me,
and I'm not going to cry at night over the
fact that I
couldn't sell sausages to fucking
vegetarians.
Ask yourself this question
if you think you seriously don't dislike
marketing.
If you got a new high-paying client every
time you
posted a video,
what would your relationship be like to
marketing?
Well then, that means you're a liar.
That means you're full of shit.
That means your marketing just sucks.
But if we can both agree that over time,
if you keep growing your
socials, your email list,
the amount of visits to your landing page,
and the amount
of conversions thereon in,
would there come a day in the next 10
years where one piece of content equals
one client?
Eventually, yes.
So how about you start doing the fucking
work,
you stop fucking moaning,
and you stop trying to imply that
marketing is the issue.
Marketing has never been the issue since
the fucking
dawn of time, since cavemen invented fire.
The fucking issue is you.
Don't blame marketing because I love
marketing. Marketing got me girls at uni.
It gets me business now.
It gets me compliments from strangers.
It put a fucking smile on the faces of
those two lads asking me to rev my car.
Marketing, if you see it right,
gives you a life you could never have
fucking
dreamed of. This isn't even my dream car.
My dream car was an Audi RS6. It
was a station wagon.
And I've already smashed past all my life
goals. I'm not even fucking 37.
Marketing's not the problem.
You're the problem.
If you want to work with me,
there's links in the descriptions.
If you don't, I don't care.
Do you know why?
Because this video wasn't about sales.
It was about marketing.